Register of the Yudenich Collection, 1919-1921
Hoover Institution Archives
Yudenich collection
1919-1921
XX048
Yudenich, Nikolay Nikolayevich, 1862-1933, collector
24 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (10.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, telegrams, reports, military documents, proclamations, maps, and printed matter, relating to the campaigns of the White Russian Severo-Zapadnaia Armiia and other aspects of the Russian Civil War, White Russian relations with the Allied Powers, and activities of White Russian representatives in Europe.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Russia. Armiia. Officers.; Russia (Territory under White armies, 1918-1920). Severo-Zapadnaia armiia.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union--History--Allied intervention, 1918-1920.
Biographical Note
1862 Born
1881 Graduated, Aleksandrovskoe Voennoe Uchilishche, St. Petersburg
1887 Graduated, Nikolaevskaia Akademiia General'nago SHtaba
1905-1907 Took part in the Russo-Japanese War. Promoted to Major-General
1912 Appointed Chief of Staff of the Kazan' Military District and promoted to Lieutenant-General
1913 Appointed Chief-of-Staff of the Caucasus Military District
1914-1915 Appointed Commander of the Caucasus and promoted to General-of-Infantry for victories in the Erzerum and Trapezund campaigns
1917 Removed from command by the Provisional Government
1918 Escaped to Finland and later Estonia
1919 Appointed Commander-in-Chief of the White forces in the North-Western Military Sector and subsequently Minister of War in the Government of the North-West by Admiral Kolchak
1920 Interned with his army in Estonia after failure of Petersburg campaign
1933 Died in Cannes, France
Scope and Content
This collection contains material related to Gen. Nikolai Yudenich's Army of the North-West, during the period of 1919-1920. It includes correspondence, reports, charts and maps dealing with military action on the Petrograd front, military action and conflicts in the Baltic area and Finland and relations between the Army of the North-West and its European allies, especially England and France. The collection was first arranged by Lieut.-Gen. Nikolai Golovin and described in two volumes entitled "Podrobnaia Opis' Del Arkhiva Severo-Zapadnago Fronta Grazhdanskoi Voiny v Rossii 1919 I 1920 Godov. S Kratkim Izlozheniem Soderzhaniia Vsekh Dokumentov Imeiushchikh Istoricheskoe Znachenie", which can be found in Box 25. The present register fully retains Gen. Golovin's arrangement, in which the material is divided into files and each page numbered consecutively.
Series Description
- ARKHIV SEVERO-ZAPODNAGO FRONTA GRAZHDANSKOI VOINY V ROSSII 1919 I 1920 GODOV, 1919-1921. (Box No. 1.-24.)
  Material related to Gen. Nikolai Yudenich's Army of the North-West dealing primarily with the military situation near Petrograd and in the Baltics as well as diplomatic relations with the Allies, including Great Britain, France, and the U.S., and negotiations with the Baltic states, especially Estonia. Includes correspondence, reports, military orders and maps, printed matter, and personal documents. The present register retains the original arrangement of Gen. Nikolai Golovin, in which the material is divided into files and each page numbered consecutively
- APPENDIX. (Box No. 25.)
  Original bound register of Gen. Nikolai Golovin entitled "Podrobnaia Opis' Del Arkhiva Severo-Zapadnago Fronta Grazhdanskoi Voiny v Rossii 1919 I 1920 Godov. S Kratkim Izlozheniem Soderzhaniia Vsekh Dokumentov Imeiushchikh Istoricheskoe Znachenie"
Container List
- ARKHIV SEVERO-ZAPODNAGO FRONTA GRAZHDANSKOI VOINY V ROSSII 1919 I 1920 GODOV
  - File 1, 1919 May-September. Miscellaneous material, including intelligence reports, telegrams, and maps related to the military situation on the Northern Front, generated by the SHtab Severo-Zapadnoi Armii, Otdel Vneshnikh Snoshenii (Col. Kruzenshtern), Razvedyvatel'noe Otdelenie and Morskaia Razvedka. Includes material re Petrograd and its environs and the Narva, Luga, Gatchina, Iamburg, and Kronstadt front (Box 1.)
    - 1-12 (Folder 1)
    - 13-27 (Folder 2)
    - 28-55 (Folder 3)
    - 56-74 (Folder 4)
    - 75-92 (Folder 5)
    - 93-126 (Folder 6)
    - 127-148 (Folder 7)
    - 149-165 (Folder 8)
    - 166-181 (Folder 9)
    - 182-198 (Folder 10)
    - 199-210 (Folder 11)
    - 211-224 (Folder 12)
    - 225-244 (Folder 13)
    - 245-263 (Folder 14)
    - 264-277 (Folder 15)
  - File 2, 1919 October-November. Same as above. Also includes excerpts from Soviet newspapers and reports re Scandinavia and the Baltic region
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 16)
    - 1-50 (Folder 17)
    - 51-72 (Folder 18)
    - 73-93 (Folder 19)
    - 94-110 (Folder 20)
    - 111-140 (Folder 21)
    - 141-163 (Folder 22)
    - 164-179 (Folder 23)
    - 180-193 (Folder 24)
    - 194-212 (Folder 25)
    - 213-234 (Folder 26)
    - 235-255 (Folder 27)
    - 235-255 (Folder 28)
    - 277-287 (Folder 29)
    - 288-309 (Folder 30)
  - File 3, 1919 November-1920 January. Same as above. Also includes copies of Soviet decrees, declarations and slogans; maps indicating troop deployment; reports re conditions in Petrograd and the relationship of Danish Syndicalists to the Soviet government
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 31)
    - 1-38 (Folder 30)
    - 39-58 (Folder 32)
    - 59-101 (Folder 33)
    - 102-126 (Folder 34)
    - 127-163 (Folder 35)
  - File 4, 1919 May-June. Same as above. Also includes material re military situation, including deployment and condition of troops (Box 2.)
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 1)
    - 1-9 (Folder 2)
    - 10-23 (Folder 3)
    - 24-38 (Folder 4)
    - 39-82 (Folder 5)
    - 83-121 (Folder 6)
    - 122-148 (Folder 7)
    - 149-190 (Folder 8)
    - 191-221 (Folder 9)
  - File 5, 1919 July-September. Same as above
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 10)
    - 1-21 (Folder 11)
    - 22-38 (Folder 12)
    - 39-61 (Folder 13)
    - 62-88 (Folder 14)
    - 89-105 (Folder 15)
    - 106-123 (Folder 16)
    - 124-131 (Folder 17)
    - 132-139 (Folder 18)
    - 140-174 (Folder 19)
    - 175-201 (Folder 20)
    - 202-236 (Folder 21)
    - 237-267 (Folder 22)
    - 268-304 (Folder 23)
    - 305-368 (Folder 24)
  - File 6, 1919 September 5-November 16. Same as above
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 25)
    - 1-25 (Folder 26)
    - 26-31 (Folder 27)
    - 32-48 (Folder 28)
    - 49-87 (Folder 29)
    - 88-114 (Folder 30)
    - 115-125 (Folder 31)
    - 126-150 (Folder 32)
    - 161-184 (Folder 33-34)
  - File 7, 1919 November-1920 January. Same as above. Also includes operational reports, mostly telegrams (Box 3.)
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 1)
    - 1-46 (Folder 2)
    - 47-91 (Folder 3)
    - 92-161 (Folder 4)
  - File 8, 1919 June-December. Same as above
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 5)
    - 1-30 (Folder 6)
    - 31-72 (Folder 7)
    - 73-150 (Folder 8)
    - 151-203 (Folder 9)
    - 204-225 (Folder 10)
    - 226-261 (Folder 11)
    - 262-298 (Folder 12)
  - File 9, 1919 December-1920 February. Same as above
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 13)
    - 1-46 (Folder 14)
    - 47-80 (Folder 15)
    - 81-127 (Folder 16)
    - 128-161 (Folder 17)
    - 162-190 (Folder 18)
    - 191-247 (Folder 19)
  - File 10, 1919 September-1920 February. Correspondence of Col. Aleksandr Brant, Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Germanii and Rossiiskaia Voennaia Missiia. Includes material re transfer of recruits from Germany to the Armies of the North-West; Libavskii Dobrovol'cheskii Strelkovyi Otriad Kniazia Livena; relations with Allies and German authorities
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 20)
    - 1-25 (Folder 21)
    - 26-69 (Folder 22)
  - File 11, 1919 May-December. Includes material re Estonia, supply (including through direct order of Winston Churchill), the military situation, relations with Omsk, the Libavskii Dobrovol'cheskii Otriad Kniazia Livena, the situation in the Baltic, and the defense of Petrograd; intelligence reports; maps; and the correspondence of Maj.-Gen. Vasilii Bezkupskii, Gen. I. Laidoner, Lieut.-Gen. Petr Glazenap, Col. K. Kruzenshtern, Gen. Nikolai IUdenich, and Lieut.-Gen. A. Gerua
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 23)
    - 1-28 (Folder 24)
    - 29-50 (Folder 25)
    - 51-70 (Folder 26)
    - 71-106 (Folder 27)
    - 107-157 (Folder 28)
    - 158-195 (Folder 29)
  - File 12, 1919 November-1920 February. Includes intelligence reports re disarmament of the Army of the North-West and the requisition of Russian property by the Estonians, relations with the Estonian government and the French, English, and American Missions in Estonia and the Estonian peace agreement with the Soviet Union; and correspondence of Gen. Nikolai Iudenich, John Allyne Gade, T. Tenison, Birk, S. Sazonov, Gen. I. Laidoner, and Lieut.-Gen. P. Glazenap (Box 4.)
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 1)
    - 1-25 (Folder 2)
    - 26-54 (Folder 3)
    - 55-87 (Folder 4)
    - 88-120 (Folder 5)
    - 121-163 (Folder 6)
    - 164-187 (Folder 7)
  - File 13. Includes intelligence reports re the situation of the Army of the North-West after the Soviet-Estonian Peace Treaty, the situation in Finland, the arrest of an anti-Bolshevik conspiracy in Petrograd, Estonian mistreatment of military and civilian refugees, the army of Maj.-Gen. S. Bulak-Balakhovich. Also includes a copy of the treaty between Estonia and the Soviet Union, and the correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. Evgenii Miller, Gen. Nikolai IUdenich, Lieut.-Gen. A. Gerua, Il'ia Bunakov-Fundaminski, Evgenii Sablin and A. Guchkov
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 8)
    - 1-16 (Folder 9)
    - 17-26 (Folder 10)
    - 27-41 (Folder 11)
    - 42-46 (Folder 12)
    - 47-53 (Folder 13)
  - File 14. Telegraph transcripts and transcripts of telephone conversations. Also correspondence of Col. K. Kruzenshtern, Major-Gen. Aleksandr Rodzianko, Gen. Nikolai IUdenich, Lieut.-Gen. Petr Glazenap, Gen. Vladimirov
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 14)
    - 1-38 (Folder 15)
    - 39-68 (Folder 16)
  - File 15. Miscellaneous material related to Helsingfors, Finland, including personnel matters and the procurement of visas. Includes correspondence of Maj.-Gen. Kondyrev, Gen. Nikolai Iudenich, and Lieut.-Gen Petr Glazenap
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 17)
    - 1-55 (Folder 18)
    - 56-115 (Folder 19)
    - 116-168 (Folder 20)
  - File 16. Correspondence between the Army of the North-West and the Estonian General Staff. Includes material re deployment of military forces, supply, conflicts between Russian and Estonian authorities (individual cases and theft of Russian military supplies), liquidation of military materiel. Includes correspondence of Col. K. Kruzenshtern; Gen. Nikolai IUdenich; Gen. I. Laidoner; Lieut.-Gen. Petr Glazenap
    - 1-28 (Folder 21)
    - 29-54 (Folder 22)
    - 55-96 (Folder 23)
    - 97-127 (Folder 24)
  - File 17. Same as above. Includes leaflets and proclamations of the Estonian government re demobilization of the Army of the North-West, the transfer of Russian troops to other anti-Bolshevik armies, conflicts with Estonians, and the work of the Liquidation Committee
    - 1-20 (Folder 25)
    - 21-35 (Folder 26)
  - File 18. Radio transcripts and reports re situation on various Civil War fronts, mostly of the French Ministère de la Guerre and Moscow Radio
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 27)
    - 1-28 (Folder 28)
    - 29-50 (Folder 29)
  - File 19. Office of the Voennyi Agent v Danii, Maj.-Gen. Sergei Pototskii. Reports, including intelligence reports re progress of the Civil War, Soviet activity in Europe and the organization of intelligence gathering and supply. Includes correspondence of Col. K. Kruzenshtern and Gen. Nikolai Iudenich (Box 5.)
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 1)
    - 1-25 (Folder 2)
    - 26-56 (Folder 3)
    - 57-85 (Folder 4)
    - 86-123 (Folder 5)
  - File 20. Office of the Voennyi Agent v Danii, Maj.-Gen. Sergei Pototskii. Material re military personnel matters, supply, public relations with European powers, arrest of Gen. Nikolai IUdenich by Maj.-Gen. S. Bulak-Balakhovich, negotiations for right of passage for former officers of the Army of the North-West. Includes correspondence of Col. K. Kruzenshtern and Lieut.-Gen. Petr Glazenap
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 6)
    - 1-35 (Folder 7)
    - 36-70 (Folder 8)
    - 71-96 (Folder 9)
    - 97-127 (Folder 10)
  - File 21. Reports and correspondence of Maj.-Gen. O. Kruzenshtern re relations of the Army of the North-West and the Polish government (Folder 11-12)
  - File 22. Financial matters, including correspondence with Estonian and British authorities (Folder 13-14)
  - File 23. Office of the Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Pol'she and Voennaia Missiia v Pol'she ot Severo-Zapadnago Fronta Russkikh Armii. Miscellaneous material re the Pinsko-Volynskaia Brigada, administrative, personnel and financial matters, relations with the Polish government and army, Col. Bermondt-Avalov's Army, the situation in the Ukraine. Includes intelligence reports, clippings from Polish newspapers, and the correspondence of Gen. Nikolai Iudenich
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 15)
    - 1-31 (Folder 16)
    - 32-49 (Folder 17)
    - 50-58 (Folder 18)
    - 59-70 (Folder 19)
    - 71-103 (Folder 20)
    - 104-129 (Folder 21)
  - File 24. Miscellaneous material re recruitment of Russian officers in Poland (Folder 22-23)
  - File 25. Office of the Commander-in-Chief, Gen. Nikolai IUdenich. Includes material re Col. Bermondt-Avalov, relations with the Polish government, and the procurement of military supplies. Also includes reports of the Commander-in-Chief, communications related to the approach to Petrograd, and correspondence with President Woodrow Wilson, Sen. William King, and John C. Groome (ARA)
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 24)
    - 1-31 (Folder 25)
    - 32-53 (Folder 26)
    - 54-86 (Folder 27)
    - 87-107 (Folder 28)
    - 108-127 (Folder 29)
  - File 26. Office of the Commander-in-Chief, Gen. Nikolai IUdenich. Includes material re military situation, relations with the Estonian government, supplies and financial matters, especially related to the Bank of Estonia, negotiations re use of railroads, decorations awarded to personnel of the American Red Cross and the French and British Missions, relations with the British Military Mission and the British government, and the demobilization of the Army of the North-West. Also includes general office correspondence and correspondence with Gen. Laidoner, Maj.-Gen. Aleksandr Rodzianko, Col. K. Kruzenshtern, S. Lianozov, V. Troitskii-Seniutovich, Sir Winston Churchill (Box 6.)
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 1)
    - 1-18 (Folder 2)
    - 19-40 (Folder 3)
    - 43-50 (Folder 4)
    - 51-70 (Folder 5)
    - 71-95 (Folder 6)
    - 1-21 (Folder 7)
    - 22-37 (Folder 8)
    - 38-54 (Folder 9)
  - File 27. Office of the Voennyi Predstavitel' Verkhovnago Pravitelia pri Soiuznykh Pravitel'stvakh i Soiuznom Verkhovnom Komandovanii, Gen. Dmitrii SHcherbachev. Includes material re relations with Estonian and Polish governments, procurement of military supplies, and plans for supplying Petrograd; official orders, protocols of meetings, and correspondence of S. Sazonov, and V. Troitskii-Seniutovich
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 10)
    - 1-32 (Folder 11)
    - 33-69 (Folder 12)
    - 70-112 (Folder 13)
    - 113-140 (Folder 14)
    - 141-178 (Folder 15)
  - File 28. Office of the Allied Military Mission in Finland and the Baltic States (Gen. Sir Hubert Gough) and the British Military Mission in Reval and Riga. Includes material re relations between the Army of the North-West and the Estonian government, British policy toward Estonia and the Army of the North-West, relations between Col. Bermondt-Avalov and the Latvian government, general situation of Col. Bermondt-Avalov's army, military supply, confiscation of military supplies by Estonian authorities, American Relief Administration and the Liquidation Commission of the Army of the North-West, and individual requests for visas. Includes correspondence of Gen. Sir Hubert Gough, Brig.-Gen. F. Marsh, Brig.-Gen. Burt, Col. K. Kruzenshtern, Gen. I. Laidoner, and Gen. Petr Glazenap
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 16)
    - 1-27 (Folder 17)
    - 28-58 (Folder 18)
    - 59-90 (Folder 19)
    - 91-126 (Folder 20)
    - 127-155 (Folder 21)
    - 156-193 (Folder 22)
    - 194-239 (Folder 23)
    - 240-271 (Folder 24)
  - File 29. Miscellaneous material re transfer of military personnel bound for the Army of the North-West from Reval to Narva. Includes lists of passengers (Folder 25-26)
  - File 30. Office of the Rossiiskii Poslannik v Stokgol'me, Konstantin Gul'kevich. Includes telegrams and other correspondence transferred to Gen. Nikolai IUdenich through Stockholm (Box 7.)
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 1)
    - 1-36 (Folder 2)
    - 37-81 (Folder 3)
  - File 31. Material re mobilization of Russian military personnel residing in Latvia, Lithuania and Estonia (Folder 4-5)
  - File 32. Material related to the American Red Cross
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 6)
    - 1-40 (Folder 7)
    - 41-85 (Folder 8)
  - File 33. Osobyi Komitet po Delam Russkikh v Finliandii. Miscellaneous material re mobilization of Russian military personnel, reports re supply of Petrograd, and intelligence reports. Includes correspondence of Gen. Nikolai IUdenich, Lieut.-Gen. Evgenii Miller, Lieut.-Gen. Gulevich (Folder 9-10)
  - File 34. Army of the North (Arkhangel'sk). Intelligence reports and other material re use of railroads and the transport of troops. Includes correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. Evgenii Miller, Col. D. Kandaurov, Col. K. Kruzenshtern (Folder 11-12)
  - File 35. Transcripts of telegrams related to the British Military Mission in Warsaw (Folder 13-14)
  - File 36. Material related to the British Mission in Riga (Folder 15-16)
  - File 37. Material related to the army of Col. Bermondt-Avalov. Includes orders of Gen. Nikolai Iudenich (Folder 17-18)
  - File 38. Material related to the British Commission for the Baltic Provinces and the British Mission in Estonia (Folder 19)
  - File 39. Reports re situation in Latvia; reports of the Commission Interalliée dans les Régions Baltiques; excerpts from the Latvian press
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 20)
    - 1-45 (Folder 21)
    - 46-72 (Folder 22)
    - 73-107 (Folder 23)
    - 108-156 (Folder 24)
    - 157-203 (Folder 25)
    - 204-239 (Folder 26)
  - File 40. Rossiiskaia Voennaia Missiia v Londone and Spetsial'naia Voennaia Missiia v Londone. Reports and correspondence, especially re political situation in Europe, aid of European powers to the White armies in the Baltic, military situation in the Baltic, personnel matters. Includes correspondence of Major-Gen. A. Gerua, K. Nabokov, and Gen. Nikolai IUdenich (Box 8.)
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 1)
    - 1-40 (Folder 2)
    - 41-76 (Folder 3)
    - 77-130 (Folder 4)
  - File 41. Same as above (Folder 5-6)
  - File 42. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Danii, Shvetsii I Norvegii. Reports, telegrams, and correspondence with other Russian representatives in Europe, mostly re relations with European powers, the military situation in the Baltic, delivery of supplies, personnel matters. Includes correspondence of Col. Dmitrii Kandaurov
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 7)
    - 1-30 (Folder 8)
    - 31-75 (Folder 9)
    - 76-125 (Folder 10)
    - 126-165 (Folder 11)
  - File 43. Mission Française en Estonie and Missions Militaires Françaises dans les Pays Baltes. Official correspondence
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 12)
    - 1-56 (Folder 13)
    - 57-105 (Folder 14)
    - 106-148 (Folder 15)
  - File 44. Lieut.-Gen. P. Glazenap. Correspondence of Col. K. Kruzenshtern (Folder 16-17)
  - File 45. Predstavitel' Glavnokomanduiushchago Severo-Zapadnoi Armii v Finliandii, Lieut.-Gen. Gulevich. Reports and correspondence re supplies, personnel matters, intelligence operations and the military situation, especially on the Ingemarland front near Petrograd
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 18)
    - 1-30 (Folder 19)
    - 31-77 (Folder 20)
    - 78-112 (Folder 21)
  - File 46. Glavnyi Nachal'nik Snabzheniia Severo-Zapadnoi Armii. Reports and correspondence re supply. Includes lists of aid from Allies and supplies confiscated by the Estonian government
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 22)
    - 1-32 (Folder 23)
    - 33-82 (Folder 24)
  - File 47. Nachal'nik Snabzheniia Severo-Zapadnoi Armii, Nachal'nik Kontseliarii Voennago Ministra Severo-Zapadnoi Rossii, and Russkii Voennyi Predstavitel' v Estonii. Reports and correspondence re supply, military personnel matters, relations with Finland and the Baltic States, especially Estonia, the kidnapping of Gen. Nikolai IUdenich by Maj.-Gen. S. Bulak-Balakhovich, and the transfer of troops from Estonia to the southern front. Includes correspondence of Gen. Petr Krasnov (Box 9.)
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 1)
    - 1-39 (Folder 2)
    - 40-90 (Folder 3)
    - 91-120 (Folder 4)
    - 121-165 (Folder 5)
    - 166-216 (Folder 6)
    - 217-256 (Folder 7)
    - 257-300 (Folder 8)
  - File 48. United States Commission for the Baltic Provinces. Reports and correspondence re situation of Russian troops in the Baltics, supply of Col. Bermondt-Avalov's army, and re Petrograd campaign. Includes correspondence of Col. Gade and Col. Kruzenshtern
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 9)
    - 1-35 (Folder 10)
    - 36-71 (Folder 11)
  - File 49. Gouvernement Provisoire de Lettonie and Ministère des Affaires Étrangères. Mostly correspondence re the repatriation of Latvian soldiers serving in the Army of the Northwest. Includes correspondence of S. Lianozov (Folder 12-13)
  - File 50. Rossiiskoe Voennoe Predstavitel'stvo v Finliandii. Material re appointment of Gen. Kondzerovskii (Folder 14-15)
  - File 51. Reports re organization of the Petrograd Army, military orders, and miscellaneous material related to the American-Russian Committee for the Relief and Salvation of Russia
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 16)
    - 1-29 (Folder 17)
    - 30-62 (Folder 18)
  - File 52. Miscellaneous office correspondence
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 19)
    - 1-40 (Folder 20)
    - 41-85 (Folder 21)
  - File 53. Reports re military situation on the Northern Front and the political situation in Europe used for official communiques
    - Original binding cover describing material included in file (Folder 22)
    - 1-38 (Folder 23)
    - 39-77 (Folder 24)
    - 78-130 (Folder 25)